<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <!-- App Settings -->
    <string name="app_name">Catch a Meteor</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <!-- Design Strings -->
    <string name="title_section1_name">Sky Map</string>
    <string name="title_section2_name">News</string>
    <string name="title_section3_name">Help</string>
    
    <!-- Intro Text -->
    <string name="intro_picth">We all at one time or another have seen a shooting star zip through the heavens. If you are interested in increasing the odds of seeing this phenomena, there are some important factors you should consider: On an annual scale, from the northern hemisphere, more random (sporadic) meteor activity will occur during the second half of the year. From the southern hemisphere, almost the opposite is true with the first half being more productive. On a daily scale, dusk is the worst time to view meteor activity. </string>
    <string name="intro_text_part1">Meteor Science is one of the few remaining astronomical fields where amateur astronomers, equipped with only their eyes, can provide a valuable service to the planetary science community. Because bright city lights and cloudy weather often prevent us from viewing the sky, chances are that few observers, if any, are watching meteors on any particular night. Brief meteor outbursts and bright fireballs can occur unnoticed. So, if you watch the sky, you may be the only observer of one of these rare events. When more observers watch each night, there is a better chance of observing and reporting fleeting meteor spectacles. This is the reason we encourage all observers to take advantage of clear skies and to observe meteor activity as often as possible.Meteor Science is one of the few remaining astronomical fields where amateur astronomers, equipped with only their eyes, can provide a valuable service to the planetary science community. Because bright city lights and cloudy weather often prevent us from viewing the sky, chances are that few observers, if any, are watching meteors on any particular night. Brief meteor outbursts and bright fireballs can occur unnoticed. So, if you watch the sky, you may be the only observer of one of these rare events. When more observers watch each night, there is a better chance of observing and reporting fleeting meteor spectacles. This is the reason we encourage all observers to take advantage of clear skies and to observe meteor activity as often as possible.</string>

    <!-- Help Text -->
    <string name="help_watch_date">Date: Always give this as the double&#8211;date over midnight no matter when in the night the watch was done, in the form year/month/date. For instance, a watch started at 1.15 a.m. on December 14th 2009 would have the date 09/12/13&#8211;14.</string>
    <string name="help_watch_time">Watch Times: Record all timings in Universal Time (UT), the same as Greenwich Mean Time, GMT. When British Summer Time (BST) is in operation, one hour must be subtracted to convert BST to UT. The time should always be quoted as a 24-hour clock, e.g. 11:10 p.m. GMT becomes 23:10 UT; 12:27 a.m. GMT becomes 00:27 UT. Start and End your watches at a specific time, rather than waiting for \"just one more meteor\", note these times down and give the watch Duration in hours and minutes. Remember to allow for any \"dead\" time during breaks or while you were not watching the sky.</string>
    <string name="help_watch_observer">Name of the observer.</string>
    <string name="help_watch_site">Site: Note the name of the nearest town or village to your observing site.</string>
    <string name="help_watch_lim_mag">Lim. Mag.: This abbreviation stands for \"limiting magnitude\" and is a measure of sky clarity. It is defined as the magnitude of the faintest star you can just see with averted vision, using exactly the same level of concentration as while meteor watching. Ideally, this should be for the area of sky observed, but the chart alongside showing the area near Polaris in Ursa Minor can be used instead. A series of other printed limiting magnitude charts for different parts of the sky as well are available for a small charge to cover copying costs; please contact the Director for details. Any changes in the lim. mag. must be recorded on the back of the form together with the times at which they happened. The best lim. mag. you can expect is about +6.5 to +7.5 in perfect skies, but +5.0 to +6.0 is common from many better UK sites. The faintest meteors visible will be mostly one or two magnitudes brighter than the lim. mag. If the lim. mag. is much worse than +5.5, observed meteor activity drops rapidly, so a dark-sky site is worth seeking.</string>
    <string name="help_watch_conditions">Conditions: If clouds are present, estimate the percentage of your field of view obscured by them (NOT for the whole sky). If this changes, record an average value about every 15 minutes. With an average of more than 20% cloud in an hour, observed rates tend to fall quite quickly. Other items to mention here include the presence of the Moon, haze, fog, mist or anything else you feel to have been of importance.</string>
    
    <string name="help_obs_time">Time: The meteor\'s appearance time to the nearest minute in UT. Timings to the nearest five seconds should be given for unusual meteors or fireballs.</string>
    <string name="help_obs_mag">Mag.: This stands for magnitude, an estimate of the brightness of the meteor to the nearest whole magnitude, as compared to some known nearby stars at the same elevation as the meteor. The constellation charts nearby can be used as a guide. Remember not to jump magnitude 0 which lies between magnitudes +1 and -1, and note the minus sign \"-\" if the meteor was of negative magnitude.</string>
    <string name="help_obs_type">Type: A meteor\'s type is either shower or sporadic. Always give the shower\'s name to avoid any ambiguity, either in full or using the standard IMO three-letter code given in our Meteor Showers List, and \"SP\" for sporadic. Please do not use other abbreviations. A rigid straight edge such as a ruler or broom-handle is very useful for tracing meteor paths back across the sky to see if they belonged to a given shower or not. If the path did not seem to intersect with a known active shower radiant, then the meteor was a sporadic.</string>
    <string name="help_obs_rel">Rel.: \"Reliability\", a measure of how well you saw the meteor, using an A, B, C scale. Class A = very well seen, Class C = poorly spotted or where some details were uncertain, while Class B = everything else. Suspected or doubtful objects should not be recorded at all, and do not be surprised if many of your meteors are of Class C.</string>
    <string name="help_obs_train">Train: Some meteors, after they have gone from the sky completely, leave a persistent glowing wake or train of ionized gas after them. Only a few bright, usually swift, meteors will leave a train, and the length of time taken for it to fade from view should be estimated in seconds or partial seconds as accurately as possible. With long duration trains lasting sometimes for minutes (very rare indeed), a degree of spreading or kinking may be apparent owing to high-altitude winds, and if this is seen a series of sketches should be done to show what happened. Note that the train has nothing to do with the time the meteor was seen in the sky for, nor the length of its path. The train is visible only after the meteor has vanished.</string>
    <string name="help_obs_notes">Notes: This allows the further description of the meteor. Features such as its relative speed (use a scale of 0 to 5, where 0 = point source/stationary, 1 = very slow, 2 = slow, 3 = medium, 4 = swift, 5 = very swift), any exceptional colour, sudden flares in brightness, or any flickering should be noted here. For fireballs, try to fix the path through the stars, or with respect to landmarks on the horizon in the case of a rare daylight fireball. Give this as a sketch, or use a star atlas to give co-ordinates for the start and end points of the track. Remember to note the direction of movement too.</string>
</resources>
